Guide to Rice University Bioengineering Department Image collection, 1997-2008 UA 388
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
[Rice University] Bioengineering Department Image Collection
1997-2008
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 388
1 Linear Feet 1 box
The collection consists of a variety of visual images--slides, CDs, and photographic prints--of people, events, and activities of the Rice University Bioengineering Department from its establishment in 1997 to 2008, when the ten-year anniversary was celebrated.
Historical Note
The Rice Department of Bioengineering was established in July 1997 and formed with the help of a Whitaker Foundation Development Award. Of the original twelve faculty, seven held primary appointments: Larry McIntire (chairman), Tony Mikos, Ka-Yia San, Jackie Shanks, Jennifer West, Kyriacos Zygourakis, and Mike Berry, holding the joint appointment with Baylor College of Medicine. The five professors with secondary appointments were John Clark, Timothy Harrigan, David Hellums, Joel Moake, and Frank Tittel. By 2008, the department had grown to nineteen faculty members and eleven multidisciplinary joint appointments with science and engineering departments at Rice, as well as forty adjunct and affiliated faculty members, primarily from the Texas Medical Center. The student population has grown to more than 115 doctoral students.
By 2008 the total research expenditures were $12.6 million. Since its founding, the Department of Bioengineering at Rice has consistently been ranked among the nation's top ten bioengineering/biomedical engineering graduate programs.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists entirely of images taken during the first ten years of the Rice Bioengineering Department. The media they represent are photographic prints, slides, and CDs. The subjects range from portraits of faculty members to posed groups of students. There are pictures of faculty and students at work, of departmental celebratory events, and of the the department's building location as well as other campus buildings.
Conditions Governing Access
The material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Recieved from Rice Bioengineering Department in 2017
Index Terms
Subjects
bioengineering; Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs
- Series I: Visual
  - Sub-Series A: Slides
    - Bahman Anvari (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Kyriakos Athanasiou (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Michael Berry (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - John Clark (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - David Hellums (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Larry McIntire (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Tony Mikos (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Robert Raphael and unknown department member (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ka Yiu San (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Jacqueline Shanks (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Jennifer West (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Kyrakos Zygourakis (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Slides used for Bioengineering Dept. brochure (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Images used in Bioengineering Dept. presentations (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bioengineering labs (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bioengineering faculty demonstrating equipment and observing students (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Portraits and group pictures of four students (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bioengineering Dept. Members at work (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - George R. Brown Hall and Campus scenes nearby (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Distinctive Rice Architecture (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series B: CDs
    - Department photographs, 2006 - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Department photographs, 2001 - 2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Summer Undergraduate Clinical Research Program, 2001, 2002, 2005, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Course Documentary, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Filming of Students giving presentations (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Images of Printed Materials - brochure, poster (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Anniversary Symposium - Valvular Heart Disease: Bioengineering from Bench to Bedside, February 6, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Article about DeBakey from Parade, May 16, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Photographs of Keck Hall (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Photograph of architect's model of Biosciences Research Collaborative (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Back-up work folder of Veronique Tran (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series C: Photographic Prints
    - Department activities and events (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Department activities and events, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Faculty, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Welcoming event for new students, August 22, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Farewell event for Dr. McIntire, 2003-08-15 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Shower for department babies, 2003-01-11 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Students and their posters, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Farewell event for Maria, 2003-09-06 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Photos of large group, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Department activities and events (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - People, April 26, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Christmas Party, December 11, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Department Activites, 1997 - March, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Department Activities, April 1999 - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Department Activities, 2001 - 2002 (Box 1, Folder 40)